{"test_questions": [[{"question": "In a combined footing if shear stress exceeds 5 kg/cm2, the nominal stirrups provided are:", "opta": "6 legged", "optb": "8 legged", "optc": "10 legged", "optd": "12 legged", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum area of tension reinforcement in beams shall not exceed", "opta": "0.15%", "optb": "1.5%", "optc": "4%", "optd": "1%", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As per I.S. 456 - 1978, the pH value of water shall be", "opta": "less than 6", "optb": "equal to 6", "optc": "not less than 6", "optd": "equal to 7", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The minimum number of main steel bars provided in R.C.C.", "opta": "rectangular columns is 4", "optb": "circular columns is 6", "optc": "octagonal columns is 8", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Post tensioning system", "opta": "was widely used in earlier days", "optb": "is not economical and hence not generally used", "optc": "is economical for large spans and is adopted now a days", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An R.C.C. column is treated as long if its slenderness ratio is greater than", "opta": "30", "optb": "35", "optc": "40", "optd": "50", "opte": "60", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The width of the flange of a T-beam should be less than", "opta": "one-third of the effective span of the T-beam", "optb": "distance between the centres of T-beam", "optc": "breadth of the rib plus twelve times the thickness of the slab", "optd": "least of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A prestressed rectangular beam which carries two concentrated loads W at L/3 from either end, is provided with a bent tendon with tension P such that central one-third portion of the tendon remains parallel to the longitudinal axis, the maximum dip h is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "A pile is a slender member which transfers the load through its lower end on a strong strata", "optb": "A pile is a slender member which transfers its load to the surrounding soil", "optc": "A pile is a slender member which transfers its load by friction", "optd": "A pile is a cylindrical body of concrete which transfers the load at a depth greater than its width.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cantilever retaining walls can safely be used for a height not more than", "opta": "3 m", "optb": "4 m", "optc": "5 m", "optd": "6 m", "opte": "8 m", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If W is the load on a circular slab of radius R, the maximum circumferential moment at the centre of the slab, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "zero", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a bent tendon is required to balance a concentrated load W at the centre of the span L, the central dip h must be at least", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For M 150 mix concrete, according to I.S. specifications, local bond stress, is", "opta": "5 kg/cm2", "optb": "10 kg/cm2", "optc": "15 kg/cm2", "optd": "20 kg/cm2", "opte": "25 kg/cm2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the average bending stress is 6 kg/cm2 for M 150 grade concrete, the length of embedment of a bar of diameter d according to I.S. 456 specifications, is", "opta": "28 d", "optb": "38 d", "optc": "48 d", "optd": "58 d", "opte": "95 d", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bottom bars under the columns are extended into the interior of the footing slab to a distance greater than", "opta": "42 diameters from the centre of the column", "optb": "42 diameters from the inner edge of the column", "optc": "42 diameters from the outer edge of the column", "optd": "24 diameter from the centre of the column", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The diameter of longitudinal bars of a column should never be less than", "opta": "6 mm", "optb": "8 mm", "optc": "10 mm", "optd": "12 mm", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The design of a retaining wall assumes that the retained earth", "opta": "is dry", "optb": "is free from moisture", "optc": "is not cohesives", "optd": "consists of granular particles", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dimensions of a beam need be changed if the shear stress is more than", "opta": "10 kg/cm2", "optb": "15 kg/cm2", "optc": "20 kg/cm2", "optd": "25 kg/cm2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The thickness of base slab of a retaining wall generally provided, is", "opta": "one half of the width of the stem at the bottom", "optb": "one-third of the width of the stem at the bottom", "optc": "one fourth of the width of the steam at the bottom", "optd": "width of the stem at the bottom", "opte": "twice the width of the steam at the bottom.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a circular slab carrying a uniformly distributed load, the ratio of the maximum negative to maximum positive radial moment, is", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "opte": "5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Thickened part of a flat slab over its supporting column, is technically known as", "opta": "drop panel", "optb": "capital", "optc": "column head", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An R.C.C. beam not provided with shear reinforcement may develop cracks in its bottom inclined roughly to the horizontal at", "opta": "25\u00b0", "optb": "35\u00b0", "optc": "45\u00b0", "optd": "55\u00b0", "opte": "60\u00b0", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The effective span of a simply supported slab, is", "opta": "distance between the centres of the bearings", "optb": "clear distance between the inner faces of the walls plus twice the thickness of the wall", "optc": "clear span plus effective depth of the slab", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following:", "opta": "In the stem of a retaining wall, reinforcement is provided near the earth side", "optb": "In the toe slab of a retaining wall, rein forcement is provided at the bottom of the slab", "optc": "In the heel slab of a retaining wall, rein forcement is provided at the top of the slab", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The minimum cube strength of concrete used for a prestressed member, is", "opta": "50 kg/cm2", "optb": "150 kg/cm2", "optc": "250 kg/cm2", "optd": "350 kg/cm2", "opte": "400 kg/cm2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The number of treads in a flight is equal to", "opta": "risers in the flight", "optb": "risers plus one", "optc": "risers minus one", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A short column 20 cm x 20 cm in section is reinforced with 4 bars whose area of cross section is 20 sq. cm. If permissible compressive stresses in concrete and steel are 40 kg/cm2 and 300 kg/cm2, the Safe load on the column, should not exceed", "opta": "4120 kg", "optb": "41, 200 kg", "optc": "412, 000 kg", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reinforced concrete beam which has width 25 cm, lever arm 40 cm, shear force 6t/cm2, safe shear stress 5 kg/cm2 and B.M. 24 mt,", "opta": "is safe in shear", "optb": "is unsafe in shear", "optc": "is over safe in shear", "optd": "needs redesigning.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a beam the local bond stress Sb, is equal to", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "None of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to I.S. : 456 specifications, the safe diagonal tensile stress for M 150 grade concrete, is", "opta": "5 kg/cm2", "optb": "10 kg/cm2", "optc": "15 kg/cm2", "optd": "20 kg/cm2", "opte": "25 kg/cm2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A foundation rests on", "opta": "base of the foundation", "optb": "subgrade", "optc": "foundation soil", "optd": "both (b) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For initial estimate for a beam design, the width is assumed", "opta": "1/15th of span", "optb": "1/20th of span", "optc": "1/25th of span", "optd": "1/30th of span", "opte": "1/40th of span.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If R and T are rise and tread of a stair spanning horizontally, the steps are supported by a wall on one side and by a stringer beam on the other side, the steps are designed as beams of width", "opta": "R + T", "optb": "T-R", "optc": "R2 + T2", "optd": "R-T", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The advantage of a concrete pile over a timber pile, is", "opta": "no decay due to termites", "optb": "no restriction on length", "optc": "higher bearing capacity", "optd": "not necessary to cut below the water mark", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the permissible compressive stress for a concrete in bending is C kg/m2, the modular ratio is", "opta": "2800/C", "optb": "2300/2C", "optc": "2800/3C", "optd": "2800/C2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If d and n are the effective depth and depth of the neutral axis respectively of a singly reinforced beam, the lever arm of the beam, is", "opta": "d", "optb": "n", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To have pressure wholly compressive under the base of a retaining wall of width b, the resultant of the weight of the wall and the pressure exerted by the retained, earth should have eccentricity not more than", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The width of the flange of a T-beam, which may be considered to act effectively with the rib depends upon", "opta": "breadth of the rib", "optb": "overall thickness of the rib", "optc": "centre to centre distance between T-beams", "optd": "span of the T-beam", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Design of a two way slab simply supported on edges and having no provision to prevent the corners from lifting, is made by", "opta": "Rankine formula", "optb": "Marcus formula", "optc": "Rankine Grashoff formula", "optd": "Grashoff formula", "opte": "Rankine-Marcus formula.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Design of R.C.C. simply supported beams carrying U.D.L. is based on the resultant B.M. at", "opta": "supports", "optb": "mid span", "optc": "every section", "optd": "quarter span.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The transverse reinforcements provided at right angles to the main reinforcement", "opta": "distribute the load", "optb": "resist the temperature stresses", "optc": "resist the shrinkage stress", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The amount of reinformcement for main bars in a slab, is based upon", "opta": "minimum bending moment", "optb": "maximum bending moment", "optc": "maximum shear force", "optd": "minimum shear force.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the effective length of a 32 cm diameter R.C.C. column is 4.40 m, its slenderness ratio, is", "opta": "40", "optb": "45", "optc": "50", "optd": "55", "opte": "60", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The percentage of minimum reinforcement of the gross sectional area in slabs, is", "opta": "0.10%", "optb": "0.12%", "optc": "0.15%", "optd": "0.18%", "opte": "0.20%", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A continuous beam shall be deemed to be a deep beam if the ratio of effective span to overall depth, is", "opta": "2.5", "optb": "2.0", "optc": "less than 2", "optd": "less than 2.5", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If T and R are tread and rise respectively of a stair, then", "opta": "2R + T = 60", "optb": "R + 2T = 60", "optc": "2R + T = 30", "optd": "R + 2T= 30", "opte": "3R + 27 = 30", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If k is wobble correction factor, \u03bc is coefficient of friction between the duct surface and the curve of tendon of radius R, the tension ratio at a distance x from either end, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a prestressed beam carrying an external load W with a bent tendon is having angle of inclination \u03b8 and prestressed load P. The net downward load at the centre is", "opta": "W - 2P cos \u03b8", "optb": "W - P cos \u03b8", "optc": "W - P sin \u03b8", "optd": "W - 2P sin \u03b8", "opte": "W + 2P sin \u03b8", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The effective width of a column strip of a flat slab, is", "opta": "one-fourth the width of the panel", "optb": "half the width of the panel", "optc": "radius of the column", "optd": "diameter of the column", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "High strength concrete is used in prestressed member", "opta": "to overcome high bearing stresses developed at the ends", "optb": "to ovecome bursting stresses at the ends", "optc": "to provide high bond stresses", "optd": "to overcome cracks due to shrinkage", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}